ALEJANDRO IGLESIAS

Francisco de Villagra 127 Ñuñoa, Santiago · +56934863816 alejandroiglesias@gmail.com

Almost 20-year experience in IT, in the financial sector, e-commerce, devops and the native cloud. The last two year I have the chance to be a teacher from a recognized University of Chile, where I put all my efforts to create the teamwork and the agility in the hearth of my students and colleagues.

EXPERIENCE

2019 - 2020

TEACHER, UNIVERSIDAD DE VALPARAISO, VALPARAISO CHILE

Teacher of Software Architecture and Web Development for students of 4th year.

2018-2021

CLOUD DEVELOPER AND ARCHITECT, TRIFENIX, SANTIAGO CHILE

We work with native cloud service for build some applications, mainly integrations, our focus is on the efficiency and low cost operations. I worked in different positions, like:

- Developer
- Architect
- Scrum Master
- Product Owner
- Devops Manager

2011-2018

ARCHITECT, DEVELOPER, CONSULTANT, AND BI LEADER, TSOFT – LATAM

(MEXICO, PERÚ Y CHILE)

Architect, developer, Consultant, Agile Coach, and BI Leader, in companies like:

- Banco Santander Chile
- Banco Santander Mexico
- PEPSICO México
- BCI Chile
- Banco de Crédito del Perú (BCP).
- Transbank Chile
- Banco Security Chile.

2010

DEVELOPER, SERCO LOGISTICS – LA SERENA

ASP .NET y Ext.js Developer

2006

DEVELOPER, LA SOLUCION REPUESTOS

Winform Developer

2005

DEVELOPER, UNIVERSIDAD CATOLICA DEL NORTE, COQUIMBO - CHILE PHP MYSQL Developer.

EDUCATION

2015

MASTER INFORMATION TECHNOLOGIES, UNIVERSIDAD SANTA MARÍA, SANTIAGO (NO GRADUATE)

2010

CIVIL COMPUTER ENGINEER, INACAP, LA SERENA

2009

COMPUTER ENGINEER, INACAP, LA SERENA, CHILE.

2008

SISTEMS ANALYST, INACAP, LA SERENA, CHILE.

2002

NETWORK TECHNICIAN, CEDUC-UCN, COQUIMBO, CHILE.

2000

SOFTWARE DEVELOPERS, INSTITUTO SUPERIOR DE COMERCIO, COQUIMBO, CHILE (TECHNICAL SECONDARY STUDIES)

ENGLISH LANGUAGE

Spoken: 60%LISTEN: 70%READ: 90%WRITE: 80%

TECHNOLOGIES APPLIED

- ASP .NET MVC
- ASP.NET
- Entity Framework
- SIGNALR
- REDIS
- DEPENDENCY INJECTION
- XUNIT

- REST
- Razor
- GRAPHQL
- SOAP
- AZURE COSMOS DB
- AZURE STORAGE
- AZURE FUNCTIONS

- SQL Server
- ORACLE RACK
- SQL Lite
- C#
- LINQ
- PATTERNS REPOSITORY, CQRS, DDD and SOLID.
- WINFORMS
- FLUTTER
- MOBX
- LINUX
- DOCKER

- AZURE COGNITIVE SEARCH
- Azure Application Insights
- ASPOSE
- TABLEAU
- SQL SERVER ANALYSIS SERVICES
- TEAM FOUNDATION SERVER
- AZURE DEVOPS
- ASPOSE
- REDUX
- REACT

ABOUT ME

I'm a software developer from my fifteen years old (I saw a computer and falling in love, like every person of my kind). In 2005 I learnt Visual Basic .NET, from there, my way has been learning more to be a better developer and contribute to other teams to make it too, with the Microsoft Stack mainly.

During my experience, I have the chance to study 6 careers, understanding that build a software is a culture of continuous learning, the technology is a medium, where the internet is the main resource of knowledge.

After almost 20 years working professionally. I have been put in practice many technologies, always looking for a solution of a big problem, taking decisions constantly. Not all of them has been precise, but every mistake has been the greatest and strong learning I ever had. The resolutions of a lots of big problems in my career is what make strong when I take up a major challenge.

RESOURCES

- 1. GITHUB
- 2. My University Class Site
- 3. My NPM packages
- 4. My Nuget packages